Guide to the Provost's Office, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Provost's office, Yale University, records
1914-1964
RU 92
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
40
(95 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and committee meeting minutes documenting the administrations of the following provosts of Yale: William A. Brown, acting (1919-1920); Williston Walker (1920-1922); Wilbur L. Cross, acting (1922-1923); Henry Solon Graves (1923-1927); Charles Seymour (1928-1937); Edgar S. Furniss (1937-1958); Norman Sydney Buck (1958-1961); Kingman Brewster, Jr., designate (1961-1963); and Charles Henry Taylor, Jr., acting (1963-1964). The records also include copies of minutes of the Yale Corporation.
Yale University. Office of the Provost
Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1919-1988
Brown, William Adams, 1865-1943
Buck, Norman Sydney, 1892-1964
Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1862-1948
Furniss, Edgar S. (Edgar Stevenson), 1890-1972
Graves, Henry Solon, 1871-1951
Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963
Walker, Williston, 1860-1922
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 3-A (YRG 3-A), Records of the Yale provost's office.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of the Provost, 1955-2002 and the Office of the President, 2014.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in two series: I. Administrative Files, 1919-1964. II. Committee Minutes, 1914-1951; and subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and committee meeting minutes documenting the administrations of the following provosts of Yale: William A. Brown, acting (1919-1920); Williston Walker (1920-1922); Wilbur L. Cross, acting (1922-1923); Henry Solon Graves (1923-1927); Charles Seymour (1928-1937); Edgar S. Furniss (1937-1958); Norman Sydney Buck (1958-1961); Kingman Brewster, Jr., designate (1961-1963); and Charles Henry Taylor, Jr., acting (1963-1964). The records also include copies of minutes of the Yale Corporation.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Office of the Provost
- Administrative files, 1919-1964; Series I
  - Accounts Examination, Comment Report, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acheson, Dean Gooderham, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative buildings with blueprints, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative reports, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Admissions, Board of, 1938-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 8)
  - Admissions and Freshman Scholarships, Department of, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Affiliated Rank and Title, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - African Studies, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Air Force, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Air Science and Tactics, Department of, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Altschul, Frank, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alumni Board, 1925-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 17)
  - Alumni Fund, 1930-1950 (Box 2, Folder 18 - 20)
  - Alumni Placement Service, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Alumni Relations, Committee on, 1939-1946 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - American Association of University Women, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1940-1956 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - American Council on Education, 1942-1953 (Box 3, Folder 25 - 26)
  - American Journal of Science, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - American Studies, 1946-1956 (Box 3, Folder 28 - 29)
  - Anatomy, Department of, 1933-1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Anthropology, Department of, 1932-1956 (Box 3, Folder 31 - 35)
  - Appointments, Bureau of, 1923-1944 (Box 4, Folder 36 - 38)
  - Architecture, Department of, 1949-1958 (Box 4, Folder 39 - 40)
  - Architecture, Painting and Sculpture, Committee on, 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Area Studies, 1946-1950 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Army Air Forces Technical Training Command, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Art, Department of, 1950-1956 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Art and Architecture, School of, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Art Gallery, 1947-1957 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Art Gallery, 1940-1946 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Arts, Division of, 1948-1955 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Asia Foundation, Book Program, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Assimilated Ranks, Faculty, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Associated Universities, Incorporated, 1947-1955 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Association of American Universities, 1939-1949 (Box 5, Folder 52 - 54)
  - Association of American Universities: Committee on Membership, 1941-1947 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Astronomy, Department of, 1952-1957 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Astronomy, Department of, 1924-1951 (Box 6, Folder 57 - 58)
  - Astrophysical Research Unit, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Athletic Association, 1926-1953 (Box 6, Folder 60 - 61)
  - Audio-Visual Service, 1950-1958 (Box 6, Folder 62 - 63)
  - Babylonian Collection, 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Bacteriology, Department of, 1942-1948 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Bakke, E. Wight, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Billings Memorial Award, 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Billings Memorial Award, 1938-1958 (Box 7, Folder 68 - 69)
  - Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory, 1938-1957 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Biochemistry, Department of, 1952-1957 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Biodynamics, Applied, 1937-1959 (Box 7, Folder 72 - 75)
  - Biodynamics, Applied: Center of Alcohol Studies, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 76 - 77)
  - Biological Sciences, Division of, 1939-1957 (Box 8, Folder 78 - 79)
  - Biology and Ecology of Man, 1951-1953 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Biophysics, Department of, 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 81 - 83)
  - Bishop Museum, 1940-1957 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Bishop Museum, 1920-1937 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Blair, Edwin Foster, 1945-1958 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Botany, Department of, 1924-1957 (Box 9, Folder 87 - 90)
  - Bronson Professorship, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Buckley, William F. Jr.: God and Man at Yale, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Budget, Corporation Committee on, 1954-1958 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    General
    See also: Corporation, box 13, folders 132-133
  - Buildings, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Bureau for Foreign Nationals, 1951-1957 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Bursar's Office, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Bursary Appointments, Committee on, 1938-1955 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Business Manager, Office of the, 1951-1958 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Canby, Henry S., 1916-1934 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1948-1957 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Central Duplicating Service, 1948-1951 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Central Records Office, 1948-1953 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Chemical Engineering, Department of, 1928-1957 (Box 10, Folder 103 - 104)
  - Chemistry, Department of, 1951-1958 (Box 10, Folder 105 - 106)
  - Chemistry, Department of, 1922-1951 (Box 11, Folder 107 - 110)
  - Cheney, Howell, 1923-1944 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Chubb Fund, 1941-1957 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Civil Aeronautics Authority, 1940-1942 (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Civil Defense, 1951-1954 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Civil Engineering, Department of, 1924-1960 (Box 11, Folder 115 - 116)
  - Classics, Department of, 1920-1936 (Box 12, Folder 117 - 119)
  - Coe, William Robertson, 1951-1957 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Cohen, Gustave, 1941-1943 (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Colleges, Residential, 1934-1958 (Box 12, Folder 122 - 124)
  - Committee on Publications, Yale University Council, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    See also: Yale University Council, box 14, folder 138
  - Commonwealth Fund: Social Aspects of Medicine, 1955-1960 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - Communication Sciences, Committee on, 1959-1962 (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - Comptroller's Office, 1954-1958 (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - Computation Center, 1956-1957 (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Coolidge Foundation, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Coordination, Committee on: Undergraduate faculties and requirements for bachelor's degrees, 1922-1923 (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - Corporation, 1929-1941 (Box 13, Folder 132 - 133)
  - Corporation By-laws, 1929-1941 (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - Corporation Educational Policy Committee, 1941-1957 (Box 13, Folder 135 - 136)
  - Corporation Educational Policy Commitee: National and International, 1934-1955 (Box 13, Folder 137)
  - Council, University, 1919-1934 (Box 14, Folder 138)
  - Council of Masters, 1938-1954 (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - Counseling, Placement and Research, Office of, 1956-1958 (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - Course of Study, Yale College, 1928-1942 (Box 14, Folder 141 - 142)
  - Cowles Foundation, 1935-1957 (Box 14, Folder 143 - 144)
  - Davis, Jerome, 1936-1939 (Box 14, Folder 145)
  - Day, George Parmly, 1928-1945 (Box 14, Folder 146 - 147)
  - Defense, 1940-1942 (Box 14, Folder 148)
  - Departmental Chairmen, 1919-1963 (Box 15, Folder 149 - 152)
  - Departmental course offerings and teaching loads, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 153)
  - Departmental Emergency Program, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 154)
  - Departmental Programs, 1948-1951 (Box 15, Folder 155 - 156)
  - DeVane, William C., 1937, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 157)
  - Development Fund, 1960-1961 (Box 15, Folder 158)
  - Directed Studies, 1946-1955 (Box 15, Folder 159)
  - Divinity School, 1955-1957 (Box 15, Folder 160)
  - Divinity School, 1923-1954 (Box 16, Folder 161 - 165)
  - Division of Science, 1956-1958 (Box 16, Folder 166)
  - Divisions: History and the Social Sciences, 1919-1931 (Box 16, Folder 167)
  - Divisions: Language and Literature, 1926-1932 (Box 16, Folder 168)
  - Divisions: Science and Mathematics, 1924-1934 (Box 16, Folder 169)
  - Divisions: Miscellaneous, 1928-1934 (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Divisions: Officers of, 1926-1931 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Drama School, 1939-1957 (Box 17, Folder 172 - 174)
  - Economics, 1937-1951 (Box 17, Folder 175 - 179)
  - Economics, Sociology and Government, 1920-1928 (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Education, Department of, 1924-1959 (Box 18, Folder 181 - 185)
  - Educational Committee, 1935-1938 (Box 18, Folder 186 - 187)
  - Educational Planning Committee, 1942-1946 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - Educational Planning Committee, 1937-1942 (Box 19, Folder 189)
  - Educational Planning Committee: Special data, 1939-1940 (Box 19, Folder 190)
  - Educational Planning Committee: Science Departments, 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 191)
  - Educational Planning Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 192)
  - Educational Policy Committee, 1919-1941 (Box 19, Folder 193 - 194)
  - Educational Policy Data, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 195)
  - Educational Supervision, Fund for, 1936-1954 (Box 19, Folder 196 - 199)
  - Electrical Engineering, Department of, 1924-1957 (Box 20, Folder 200 - 202)
  - Employment policy, 1939-1944 (Box 20, Folder 203)
  - Employment Relations, Advisory Committee on, 1940-1944 (Box 20, Folder 204)
  - Endowments and Gifts, Committee on, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 205)
  - Engineering, School of, 1938-1956 (Box 20, Folder 206 - 210)
  - Engineering, School of, 1926-1937 (Box 21, Folder 211)
  - Educational Supervision, Fund for (Box 21, Folder 212)
  - Engineering, Yale Committee on, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 213)
  - Engineering Mechanics, Department of, 1924-1940 (Box 21, Folder 214)
  - English, Department of, 1925-1957 (Box 21, Folder 215 - 220)
  - Eno Foundation, 1942-1943 (Box 21, Folder 221)
    See also: Post War Planning and Reconstruction, box 54, folder 521
  - Enrollment and Scholarship, Committee on, 1943-1956 (Box 21, Folder 222)
  - European Economic Community: Hans von der Groeben, Council of Ministers, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 223)
  - F, 1941-1958 (Box 22, Folder 224)
  - Faculty: Extra stipends, 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 225)
  - Faculty and Staff Children Scholarships, 1956-1960 (Box 22, Folder 226)
  - Faculty Club, 1950-1955 (Box 22, Folder 227)
  - Faculty Lists, 1932-1934 (Box 22, Folder 228)
  - Faculty Lists: inactive, 1930-1932 (Box 22, Folder 229 - 230)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1951-1958 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1932-1951 (Box 23, Folder 232 - 236)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Executive Committee of Budgets, 1929-1933 (Box 23, Folder 237)
  - Faculty Salaries, 1951-1955 (Box 23, Folder 238 - 239)
  - Far Eastern Studies, 1936-1940 (Box 23, Folder 240)
  - Faculty Salaries: Working Papers, 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 241)
  - Faculty Salary Investigation, 1934-1935 (Box 23, Folder 242)
  - Fluid Research Fund, 1936-1940 (Box 23, Folder 243)
  - Financing, Higher Education, Committee on, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 244)
  - Fine Arts, School of, 1927-1955 (Box 24, Folder 245 - 249)
  - Fisher, Samuel H., 1922-1935 (Box 24, Folder 249A)
  - Fluid Research Fund, 1949-1957 (Box 25, Folder 250 - 251)
  - Ford Foundation, College Grants Program Questionnaire, 1938-1948 (Box 25, Folder 252)
  - Ford Foundation, Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 253)
  - Ford Foundation, General, 1952-1957 (Box 25, Folder 254)
  - Ford Foundation, Grants-in-Aid, 1956-1957 (Box 25, Folder 255)
  - Ford Foundation, Interdisciplinary Grants, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 256 - 257)
  - Foreign Area Studies, 1950-1956 (Box 25, Folder 258)
  - Foreign Area Studies, 1951-1957 (Box 26, Folder 259 - 260)
  - Forestry, School of, 1942-1950 (Box 26, Folder 261 - 265)
  - Forestry, School of: Hartford Foundation, 1923-1957 (Box 26, Folder 266)
    See: Hartford, John A. Foundation, box 31, folders 308-310
  - Franklin Papers Project, 1953-1957 (Box 26, Folder 267)
  - Fraternities, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 268)
  - French, Department of, 1929-1957 (Box 27, Folder 269 - 273)
    See also: Romance Languages box 57, folder 555
  - Freshman Year, 1937-1958 (Box 27, Folder 274 - 276)
  - Freshman Year, 1927-1937 (Box 28, Folder 277)
  - Fringe Benefits, 1956-1961 (Box 28, Folder 278 - 279)
  - Fulbright Awards, 1927-1937 (Box 28, Folder 280)
  - Fundraising, Committee on, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 281)
  - G, 1950-1962 (Box 28, Folder 282)
  - Garland Fund, 1930-1940 (Box 28, Folder 283)
  - Geochronometric Laboratory, 1940-1957 (Box 28, Folder 284)
  - Geography, Department Of, 1923-1963 (Box 28, Folder 285 - 287)
  - Geology, Department of, 1926-1957 (Box 29, Folder 288 - 289)
  - German, Department of, 1924-1957 (Box 29, Folder 290 - 292)
  - Goethe Project, 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 293)
  - Government Contracts, 1951-1957 (Box 29, Folder 294 - 296)
  - Government contracts, Summer, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 297)
  - Graduate and Professional Schools, Commission on, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 298)
  - Graduate and Undergraduate Expenses, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 299)
  - Graduate School, 1921-1957 (Box 30, Folder 300 - 302)
  - Graduate Woman's Dormitory: Helen Hadley Hall, 1955-1959 (Box 30, Folder 303 - 304)
  - Grants for Scientific Research, Committee on, 1945-1950 (Box 30, Folder 305)
  - Grants for Scientific Research, Committee on, 1943-1944 (Box 31, Folder 306)
  - Hadley, Morris, 1952-1954 (Box 31, Folder 307)
  - Hartford, John A. Foundation, 1954-1957 (Box 31, Folder 308 - 310)
  - Hartford Foundation Material: Edgar S. Furniss, 1955-1957 (Box 31, Folder 311 - 312)
  - Harvard, 1960-1961 (Box 31, Folder 313)
  - Havana-Alumni Fellowship, 1946-1948 (Box 31, Folder 314)
  - Health Department: Brouha project, 1937-1940 (Box 31, Folder 315)
  - Health Department, Yale University, 1922-1944 (Box 32, Folder 316)
  - Heidelberg-Yale Exchange, 1951-1954 (Box 32, Folder 317)
  - Highway Traffic, Bureau of, 1938-1961 (Box 32, Folder 318)
  - History, Department of, 1938-1959 (Box 32, Folder 319 - 324)
  - History, Department of, 1920-1937 (Box 33, Folder 325 - 328)
  - History, The Arts and Letters, 1932-1946 (Box 33, Folder 329)
  - History of Art, Department of, 1939-1957 (Box 33, Folder 330 - 331)
  - History of Yale, 1940-1949 (Box 33, Folder 332)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1938-1963 (Box 33, Folder 333)
  - Hotchkiss Fund, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 334)
  - Housing, Committee on, 1938-1959 (Box 33, Folder 335)
  - Hoyt Fund, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 336)
  - Humanistic Studies, Executive Committee on, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 337)
  - Human Relations Area Files, Incorporated, 1949-1962 (Box 34, Folder 338)
  - Human Resources, Study of, 1951-1954 (Box 34, Folder 339)
  - I, 1948-1956 (Box 34, Folder 340)
  - Inclusive Fee, 1941-1952 (Box 34, Folder 341)
  - Industrial Administration, Department of, 1948-1955 (Box 34, Folder 342 - 343)
  - Industrial Engineering, Department of, 1926-1932 (Box 34, Folder 344)
  - Industrial Relations, 1932 (Box 34, Folder 345)
  - Information, Director of, 1956-1961 (Box 34, Folder 346)
  - Inquiries, Concerning Policy, 1947-1953 (Box 34, Folder 347 - 349)
  - Institute of Far Eastern Languages, 1945-1961 (Box 35, Folder 350 - 353)
  - Institute of Human Relations, 1945-1961 (Box 35, Folder 354 - 355)
  - Institute of Human Relations: correspondence, 1936-1944 (Box 35, Folder 356 - 357)
  - Institute of Human Relations: organization, 1928-1935 (Box 36, Folder 358 - 360)
  - Institute of Human Relations, Executive Committee, 1928-1936 (Box 36, Folder 361)
  - Institute of International Studies, 1936-1952 (Box 36, Folder 362 - 363)
  - Institute of International Studies, Advisory Council, 1943-1947 (Box 36, Folder 364 - 366)
  - Institute of International Studies: Anglo-American, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 367)
  - International Exchange, 1952-1957 (Box 37, Folder 368)
  - International Relations, Department of, 1945-1957 (Box 37, Folder 369)
  - International Studies Fund, Overbrook Foundation, 1949-1962 (Box 37, Folder 370 - 371)
  - Italian Student Exchange, 1953-1955 (Box 37, Folder 372)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 373)
  - Judaica Research Project, 1944-1956 (Box 37, Folder 374 - 375)
  - K, 1937-1955 (Box 37, Folder 376)
  - Labor-Management Center, 1945-1956 (Box 37, Folder 377)
  - Labor-Management Center, Policy Committee, 1946 (Box 37, Folder 378)
  - Law, School of, 1939-1957 (Box 38, Folder 379 - 386)
  - Law, School of, 1924-1939 (Box 39, Folder 387 - 391)
  - Law, School of, Council's Committee on, 1948-1961 (Box 39, Folder 392 - 393)
  - Liberal Arts, Committee on, 1942-1949 (Box 39, Folder 394)
  - Librarianship, 1937-1939 (Box 39, Folder 395)
  - Library, 1930-1951 (Box 40, Folder 396 - 401)
  - Library, 1924-1929 (Box 41, Folder 402)
  - Library, Medical School, 1940-1944 (Box 41, Folder 403)
  - Linguistics, Department of, 1939-1963 (Box 41, Folder 404)
  - Map Laboratory, 1950-1963 (Box 41, Folder 405)
  - Married Student Housing, 1954-1955 (Box 41, Folder 406)
  - Master of Arts in Teaching Program, 1951-1962 (Box 41, Folder 407)
  - Mathematics, Department of, 1932-1957 (Box 41, Folder 408 - 410)
  - Mathematics, Department of, 1924-1931 (Box 42, Folder 411)
  - Mechanical Engineering, Department of, 1925-1957 (Box 42, Folder 412)
  - Medical Affairs, Director of, 1947-1961 (Box 42, Folder 413)
  - Medicine, School of, 1949-1960 (Box 42, Folder 414 - 418)
  - Medicine, School of, 1919-1949 (Box 43, Folder 419 - 427)
  - Medicine, School of, Committee upon the Deanship and Administrative Organization of, 1945-1946 (Box 44, Folder 428)
  - Mercer Estate, 1939 (Box 44, Folder 429)
  - Merchant Seamen Studies, 1945-1951 (Box 44, Folder 430)
  - Microbiology, Department of, 1949-1956 (Box 44, Folder 431)
  - Military Information, Bureau of, 1942-1943 (Box 44, Folder 432)
  - Military Intelligence School, 1942-1945 (Box 44, Folder 433)
  - Military Science, Department of, 1933-1963 (Box 44, Folder 434)
  - Military Studies Program, Committee on, 1959 (Box 44, Folder 435)
  - Modern Foreign Languages, Committee on, 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 436)
  - Morse Research Fellowships, 1950-1963 (Box 44, Folder 437 - 440)
  - Music, Department of, 1942-1957 (Box 44, Folder 441 - 442)
  - Music, Department of, 1945-1952 (Box 45, Folder 443 - 445)
  - Music, School of, 1924-1944 (Box 45, Folder 446)
  - Music, School of, Committee on, 1939-1940 (Box 45, Folder 447)
  - National Policy, 1947-1953 (Box 45, Folder 448)
  - National Research, 1938-1959 (Box 45, Folder 449)
  - National Youth Administration, 1938-1939 (Box 45, Folder 450)
  - Naval Science and Tactics, 1928-1939 (Box 45, Folder 451)
  - Near Eastern Languages and Literature, Department of, 1946-1957 (Box 46, Folder 452 - 453)
  - New Haven Hospital, 1944-1953 (Box 46, Folder 454)
  - News Bureau: releases, 1962-1963 (Box 46, Folder 455)
  - News Bureau: selected, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 456)
  - Norfolk Music School, 1940-1952 (Box 46, Folder 457)
  - Nuclear Science Laboratory, 1946 (Box 46, Folder 458)
  - Nursing, School of, 1952-1960 (Box 46, Folder 459 - 462)
  - Nursing, School of, 1923-1951 (Box 47, Folder 463 - 465)
  - Nutrition, Institute of, 1938-1940 (Box 47, Folder 466)
  - Nutrition, Laboratory of, 1942-1950 (Box 47, Folder 467)
  - Oak Street Redevelopment, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 468 - 470)
  - Oak Street Redevelopment, 1952-1956 (Box 48, Folder 471 - 473)
  - Occupational Medicine and Hygiene, Institute of, 1944-1949 (Box 48, Folder 474)
  - O'Hearn, Charles M., Assistant to the President, 1952-1961 (Box 48, Folder 475)
  - Oksenburg Foundation, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 476)
  - Oriental Studies, 1935-1946 (Box 48, Folder 477 - 478)
  - Patents, 1947-1958 (Box 48, Folder 479)
  - Patents, Committee on, 1957-1958 (Box 48, Folder 480)
  - Peabody Museum, 1926-1957 (Box 49, Folder 481 - 484)
  - Personnel Department, 1948-1956 (Box 49, Folder 485)
  - Personnel Officer, 1939-1947 (Box 49, Folder 486 - 487)
  - Pharmacology, Department of, 1944-1955 (Box 50, Folder 488)
  - Philosophy, Department of, 1928-1958 (Box 50, Folder 489 - 493)
  - Philosophy and Psychology, Departments of, 1925-1931 (Box 50, Folder 494)
  - Physical Education, Department of, 1943-1956 (Box 51, Folder 495)
  - Physical Sciences and Mathematics, Division of, 1943-1958 (Box 51, Folder 496)
  - Physics, Department of, 1940-1956 (Box 51, Folder 497 - 502)
  - Physics, Department of, 1920-1939 (Box 52, Folder 503)
  - Physiological Chemistry, Department of, 1930-1952 (Box 52, Folder 504)
  - Physiology, Department of, 1937-1954 (Box 52, Folder 505)
  - Poems of Restoration England, 1956-1958 (Box 52, Folder 506)
  - Policy Inquiries, 1953-1958 (Box 52, Folder 507 - 509)
    See also: Inquiries, Concerning Policy, box 34, folders 347-349
  - Political Science, Chairmanship of, 1950-1952 (Box 52, Folder 510)
  - Political Science, Department of, 1958-1964 (Box 52, Folder 511)
  - Political Science, Department of, 1934-1957 (Box 53, Folder 512 - 518)
  - Political Union, 1937-1939 (Box 53, Folder 519)
  - Post-War Education, 1942-1945 (Box 53, Folder 520)
  - Post-War Planning and Reconstruction, Committee on, 1942-1945 (Box 54, Folder 521)
  - Pre-Induction Scholarships, 1951-1953 (Box 54, Folder 522)
  - President's Special Committee on the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1958-1959 (Box 54, Folder 523)
  - Primate Biology, Laboratories of, undated (Box 54, Folder 524)
  - Professional Schools Expansion, 1928-1930 (Box 54, Folder 525)
  - Projects, Committee on Clearance of, 1945-1950 (Box 54, Folder 526)
  - Promotions and Tenure, Committee on, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 527)
  - Provost, Office of: copies of form letters, 1953-1958 (Box 54, Folder 528 - 529)
  - Psycho-clinic, 1943-1957 (Box 55, Folder 530)
  - Psychology, Committee on (Clinical), 1944-1945 (Box 55, Folder 531)
  - Psychology, Department of, 1943-1957 (Box 55, Folder 532 - 537)
  - Psychology, Department of, 1928-1942 (Box 56, Folder 538)
  - Public Health, Department of, 1944-1961 (Box 56, Folder 539 - 541)
  - Puerto Rico, University of: Marine Biology and Oceanography, 1953-1954 (Box 56, Folder 542)
  - Rabinowitz, Louis M., 1950-1958 (Box 56, Folder 543)
  - Race Relations, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 544)
  - Registration, Director of, 1945-1956 (Box 56, Folder 545)
  - Religion, Department of, 1924-1957 (Box 56, Folder 546 - 547)
  - Retirement Allowance Plan, 1926-1927 (Box 56, Folder 548)
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps, 1949-1951 (Box 56, Folder 549)